about a year and a half ago
i lived by the sea i had nearly all my
life
as the daughter of a naval officer the
ocean was a constant friend throughout
my childhood
i loved the sea and i felt that it left
me back
then one day while looking out to the
exact
point where the sky meets the water i
realized that i needed to say goodbye
this life was what i'd always known and
it reflected how i felt
i was afraid of risk so much so that i
was more willing to keep my current job
not because it suited me but because it
was comfortable
i also knew that i had allowed a very
bad habit into my life
and that was giving my mind permission
to criticize everything i did
only seeing where i had failed where i
could have done better
where i hadn't loved enough
and so i began to wander and after many
failed attempts at rebuilding i found my
new home
far from the sea enveloped by endless
mountains and trees
i didn't feel any different and it was
humbling to realize that you can't
escape who you are
no matter how you distance yourself
after years of searching i accepted that
happiness isn't a place on earth
i had to start with my own mind which
insisted on chastising every single
thing i did
i had to stop believing that what i
wanted was unattainable
and dare to see worth and who i am just
as i am and that maybe what i want
isn't what will make me happy
[Music]
as i stop trying to write my future
exactly as i envisioned it
my life became more meaningful but not
easier than i thought it could be after
years of living in cities surrounded by
people
i found love in a rural town which was
the last thing i expected
and taught me how with patience and
faith things can work out
a new swell of creativity came over me
by working to
live instead of vice versa accepting a
smaller salary in exchange
for the beauty of my home
[Music]
my fantasies i realized had to
compromise
and i needed to embrace opportunities
that were right in front of me
instead of the ones i wished were there
i got a job that offered stability even
though my ideal type of work was far
from it surprisingly it was just what i
needed
to teach me that one of our missions in
life is to give
and by giving my time to my community as
a teacher i was filling a void that
always doubted
that i as one person could make a
difference
as you can too
[Music]
this week i had an awful cold and spent
much of it in bed
but i did try to motivate myself to tidy
up a bit in preparation for winter
and air out my woollens the transition
between seasons made me start to
reminisce about this year
and how wonderful it has been to share
some of it with you
i've learned so much about myself and
i encourage you to be proud of what
you've accomplished in your life
and yet humbled by what there is still
to learn
wherever you are wherever you live you
can begin cultivating a mind that is
enriching
instead of diminishing where do you
focus your energy
if you're at all like me and have a
tendency to see your flaws
over your strengths i encourage you to
cultivate a gentleness of spirit
that will guide you towards your inner
light hold on to it
and dare to be proud of who you are in a
world where we might be made to feel
ashamed of ourselves
and where we come from
[Music]
uh
do
[Music]
you